Guide to the Hugh Heclo government policy collection, 1901-1991
George Mason University Libraries
- Hugh Heclo government policy collection
  - Memos of Support for Viet Nam 9/30/66 - 12/3/66 (Box 12, Folder 4 D)
    Includes an indication that President Johnson consulted President Eisenhower
  - Minutiae Brought to the President's Attention 1/30/67 - 7/24/67 (Box 12, Folder 4 E)
    Schedule for the night, number of antelope delivered to ranch, etc.
  - Consensus of Public Opinion 3/25/68 - 11/8/68 (Box 12, Folder 4 G)
  - Balance of Payments 3/5/65 - 2/12/66 (Box 12, Folder 4 H)
  - Daily Diary and Presidents Appointments 7/8/64 - 3/2/65 (Box 13, Folder 1 A)
    includes Staff background notes for President Appointments
  - Papers from the Government Service of Sydney Stein, Jr. 8/9/40 - 11/6/64 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    also contains a summary of Mr. Stein's Federal work history
  - Study of the 1960 - 1961 Presidential Transition 10/25/60 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    The paper focuses on the White House and Executive Office organization structure was prepared by the Brookings Institution and provides a history of transitions from 1939.
  - White House History JFK 12/29/62 - 1/29/63 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    NOT a history; the papers record discussion to create a history
  - White House Staff JFK 1/23/61 - 12/3/63 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Transition 1961 11/9/60 - 3/16/61 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Cabinet - Kinter 3/25/65 - 5/11/67 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - LBJ - IGR [Intergovrnment Relations ] 7/29/65 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - LBJ - Anna's Notes (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - List of Potential Researchers (Box 13, Folder 10)
    also material related contains research sources
  - National Security Org 9/1972 - 4/1980 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Task Force Government Organization and Reorganization 8/27/79 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    contains written finding aid to LBJ papers
  - FDR 1 of 2 5/1/33 - 2/15/45 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    includes phone logs of Mr. Coy Director of Budget
  - FDR 2 of 2 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    contains notes and other material regarding FDR Truman Library and other sources of i
  - Historical Materials in the Herbert Hoover Presidential Library (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Historical Resources of the John F. Kennedy Library (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Heclo [OWMR and Economic Council] 3/6/46 - 8/25/80 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    papers related to Office of War Mobilization and Reconversion and Economic Council]
  - Historical Materials in the Truman Library 1/1979 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    a National Archives and Records Service pamphlet describing the holdings at the library
  - The Presidential Documents Series 1980 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    a catalogue pamphlet published by University Publications of America, Inc. describing its products and prices
  - Staff Work for the President and the Executive Branch 8/20/54 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Instructions from the President on how he wants staff work to be done
  - Historical Materials in the Dwight D. Eisenhower Library 5/1977 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Historical Materials in the John F. Kennedy Library 1978 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Historical Materials in the Lyndon B. Johnson Library 1977 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - The era of Franklin D. Roosevelt: A Selected Bibliography of Periodical, essay and Dissertation Literature, 1945 - 1971 1/30/74 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    Publication of the National Archives and Records Service, documents listed in the publication are available at the library
  - Observations of Models of the Presidency Lester G. Seligman 4/10/80 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Surviving, Coping, and Developing EOP: The Staffing Connection (Box 15, Folder 9)
    Executive office of the President
  - Missouri Library Association Quarterly Vol. XXI, No. 3, September 1960 9/1960 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    the publication included an article; "The Harry S. Truman Library by Miss Betty Herscher
  - The Harry S. Truman Library: Creation of the State Israel Bibliographical Suggestions 11/5/74 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - The Harry S. Truman Library: 1948 Presidential Campaign and Election, Bibliographical Suggestions 11/18/74 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - The Harry S. Truman Library: U.S. Foreign Relations 1945 - 1953, Bibliographical Suggestions 11/14/74 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Bibliography on the Potsdam Conference (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - The Truman Committee Bibliography 7/9/75 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - The Harry S. Truman Library, Bibliographical Suggestions, The Marshall Plan (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Korean War, Bibliographical Suggestions, 10/19/77 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Report of the President's Task Force on Government Organization 11/6/64 and 11/10/64 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    also included is the Statement of Elmer B. Staats before the Committee on Government Operations (1/7/66)
  - Framework for the Future; A Study of the Organization of OMB 6/1979 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Eisenhower and Dulles: Who Made the Decisions? Autumn 1979 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    a reprint of a magazine article by Richard H. Immerman
  - Political Science Quarterly, Winter 1979 - 80 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    includes an article Eisenhower as an Activist President, by Fred I. Greenstein
  - Organizing the Presidency by Stephen Hess 1976 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - The Economy: Recessions, 1954 and 1957-58 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Public Expectations and the Presidency 2/1/80 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Presidential Power, Richard E. Neustadt 5/7/80 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    transitions
  - President Eisenhower and the Defense Budget 8/77 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - The Crisis of Competence in Government (Box 16, Folder 6)
    by James L. Sundquist
  - Journal of Central Mississippi Valley American Studies Association, Spring 1960 Spring 1960 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    Article by Phillip D. Lagerquist, "The Harry S. Truman Library - - A New Research Center for the Middle West
  - Taxation (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Inflation (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Labor Disputes (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Housing (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Health (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Education (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Agriculture (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Foreign Policy (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Collective Security (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Council of Economic Advisors (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Reorganization of Gov[ernmen]t Dep[artmen]t[s] (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Government Employees (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Social Security - Unemployment Insurance (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Bureau of Budget - Correspondence 8/2/44 - 8/13/68 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    Correspondence to and from Sydney Stein, Jr.
  - U.S. Government Panel to Review Government Salaries 1 of 2 12/7/62 - 4/12/65 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - U.S. Government Panel to Review Government Salaries 2 of 2 12/28/61 - 5/21/63 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - B[ureau] of B[udget] Gover[ermen]t Task Force (Reorganization 6/5/64 - 12/15/64 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Budget Bureau SSJR 1 of 3 6/19/40 -12/14/44 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Budget Bureau SSJR [Sydney Stein, Jr.] 2 of 3 1/29/41 - 8/17/67 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    Bulk of material in calendar year 1943
  - Interview - Averell Harriman (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Dwight Ink 3/18/80 and 7/16/80 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    Mr. Ink served in policy making positions under 7 Presidents he was influential in establishing OMB, EPA and the Postal Service as a government corporation
  - McDonald Tape - Hughes, Price, Easer 2/8/80 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Kieffer, Jarold (Box 17, Folder 9)
    Presidential Advisor Truman - Reagan
  - Murphy [interview] (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - [Interview of ]Fred McNamara 12/3/79 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - [Interview of] Millet, John D. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Interview -James W. Rowe,Jr. 5/10/64, 9/9/69, 6/79 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    3 separate interviews
  - Oral Interview/ Stone, Don 1979 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Interview, The Truman White house 2/20/80 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    Interviewees were Charles Murphy, James Webb, David Stone, and Richard Neustadt
  - Notes, Elsey 7/1/80 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - William Capren 7/10/80 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Interview William Carey 5/79 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Interview with Hale Champion 6/30/80 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Interview - Joseph P. Harris 12/7/79 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Notes William Hopkins 6/23/80 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Arthur Maass Interview notes 1/17/80 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Conversation with Arthur Minnich 7/31/80 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Don K. Price 7/10/80 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Bradley Patterson 6/25/80 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Maxwell Rabb 6/26/80 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Joe Rauh 7/3/80 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Mrs. Ann Whitman (Box 18, Folder 18)
    file only contains a note of Mrs. Whitman's expenses
  - Summary notes of the Following Interviews 7/22/80 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - A Nelson (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Interview with White House Staff FDR and HST 5/14/48 - 9/1/48 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Truman White House 5/17/48 - 2/17/53 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Oral History Session (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Oral history DDE 12/1966 - 1/30/68 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Interview Gordon Gray 6/25/75 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Interview - Stephen Horn 4/10/68 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    Stephen Horn DID these interviews of White House personnel during DDE presidency
  - Oral Interviews - Candidates For 2/22/79 - 7/8/80 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Interview - Donald Dawson (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Bernard Gladieux 3/17/80 - 7/16/80 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Luther Gulick 2/28/80 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - W. Heller Oral History 12/14/77 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Requests for Reproduction from Various Sources (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - National Academy of Public Administration 5/30/79 - 8/5/80 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    Correspondence related to the study of the President and Administrative Management
  - Libraries - Bills 5/19/80 - 8/15/80 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    bills for photocopy from Presidential Libraries
  - Truman Library - Bibliographical Suggestions 4/1960 - 10/19/77 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Eisenhower Library Finding Aid 10/1968 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    includes 3 monographs: Partnership for Research (describes role of Sherman Adams in Eisenhower administration, John Foster Dulles' "Letter of Gift", Party Politics in the Eisenhower Administration
  - Truman Library Finding Aid 4/1960 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Destler 10/3/79 - 8/1/80 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    I.M.Dester was a senior associate at the Carngie Endowment for International Peace and participated in the study of the President and Administrative Management
  - Mackenzie 9/6/79 - 7/30/80 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    Cal Mackenzie of Colby College participated in the study of the President and Administrative Management
  - The U.S. Presidential Libraries and the History of Political Economy Fall 1976 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    Author James L. Cochrane, University of South Carolina
  - PACGO 1958 1/98/58 - 12/23/58 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    President's Advisory Committee on Government Organization
  - PACGO 1959 2/27/59 - 11/24/59 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - PACGO 1960 1/22/60 - 5/29/60 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Transition 1960 11/3/60 - 1/19/61 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Neustadt Memo 11/30/60 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    Memo entitled "Staffing The President-Elect
  - Space Council JFK 1/1/62 - 8/2/63 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Interdepartmental Concerns JFK 2/16/61 - 4/4/61 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - JFK, CEA (Box 20, Folder 14)
    Council of Economic Advisers
  - JFK, NSC. 8/8/47 - 11/21/61 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - JFK L[ibrary] 4/18/80 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Heiman 7/24/80 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    telephone conversation with Dave Davis, Exec. Dir. Mass. Port Authority
  - Brookings Study Transition 1960 - 1961 11/11/1960 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Goodpaster Oral Interview 10/11/77 - 1/16/78 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Ash 1972 11/7/72 - 10/16/80 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    Ash Council
  - PACGO 1952 - 1953 12/14/52 - 6/12/53 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - EAP PACGO General 1/12/53 - 12/7/60 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - PAGCO 1954 6/27/54 - 12/14/54 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - PACGO 1955 1/25/55 - 11/1/55 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - PACGO 1956 4/2/56 - 12/27/56 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - PACGO 1957 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Shanley Diary (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - W[hite] H[ouse] Intergovt Relations 3/5/56 - 11/9/59 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - WHO Cab[inet] Sec[retariat] 7/6/53 - 11/21/59 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - WHO House Keeping 12/8/53 - 11/9/60 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - White House Org.Misc 1/14/53 - 12/4/58 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - White House Staff 11/21/52 - 7/28/80 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    7/28/80 document summarizes material on organization during Eisenhower administration
  - NSC 12/27/52 - 6/1980 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Nixon 2/3/58 - 2/28/58 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    Letter from Eisenhower to Nixon and reply concerning transfer of power to Vice President in the event of Eisenhower's incapacity to fulfill office
  - DDE Reorganization - First Secretary 3/19/56 - 1/22/60 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Personnel 11/29/49 - 6/28/79 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Reorg[anization] OPM 10/2/57 - 1/23/59 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - D[wight]D E[isenhower] Activities Schedule 1/28/55 - October 1957 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    DDE = D D Eisenhower
  - D[wight]D E[isenhower] Adams 11/5/52 - 3/30/56 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - BOB 4/7/53 - 9/24/59 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - D[wight]D E[isenhower] Conference 1/19/56 - 1/1/57 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Dulles 1/21/53 - 11/10/58 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Staff Meeting - FDR 4/24/42 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - FDR - General 2/20/36 - 7/28/80 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Leahy 9/7/42 9/4/46 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    photo copies of diary
  - Brownlou 1936 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - CEA 4/1/53 - 1/3/61 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Econ. Policy 11/30/59 - 1/17/61 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Palen [Council on Foreign Economic Policy] DDE 1/18/54 - 1/20/61 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - DDE Perception 11/10/52 - 12/8/58 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    Dwight D Eisenhower
  - DDE - Hegerty 12/9/58 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    Advice from Jim Hagerty to Eisenhower on how the Office of the President should function in the last 2 years of his term
  - DDE - Harlow 3/21/53 - 9/1/53 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Hoover Comm[ision] 9/28/55 - 6/27/58 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Jackson Subcommittee 6/4/59 - 6/14/60 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    Senator Jackson's subcommittee dealt with "National Policy Machinery"
  - Budget Bureau 1949 - 62 12/5/10 - 1/20/61 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    BOB documents regarding management improvement in the executive Branch and the Executive Office of the President; also includes an undated document summarizing the development of the EOP organization
  - McGeary - BOB 1/20/55 - 3/24/80 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - The Bureau of the Budget and the Development of American Fiscal Policy 1939 - 1945 4/17/80 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    Research paper by John William McKenzie Barber
  - Notes on Conversation with George Elsey 1/4/46 - 2/17/64 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Office Memorandum 5/6/46 4/11/46 - 12/22/52 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    includes several documents regarding the Office of War Mobilization and Reconversion
  - 1944 - 1947 OWMR, CEA, NSC, etc. 9/24/46 - 7/14/80 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    9/24/46 document forwards a then classified summary of US-USSR relations
  - Interview with Bernard L Gladieux 3/17/80 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Joint Oral History Interview: The Truman White House 1 of 2 11/13/80 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    Charles S. Murphy, David Stonwe, James Webb, and Richard Neustadt
  - Joint Oral History Interview: The Truman White House 2 of 2 12/4/80 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Interview with Keyserling 11/28/80 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - TA/HC Norton on WH Org 9/15/10 - 9/11/80 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    Taft Commission on White House Organization
  - "Dear Mr. President.. ." by Ira R,T. Smith with Joe Alex Morris 1949 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Managing the Federal Government: The Role of the President by Hugh Heclo 6/3/80 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Appendix to Doctrine of Presidential Management (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Overview of Management and the Presidential Office 2/16/57 - 7/28/80 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    Assorted papers: Harlod Smith and Truman, Breuer as informal asst. to FDR in 1933, How the DDE White House worked, Stein's government service, Appleby on relationship of Tugwell and Hopkins to FDR
  - interview Conducted by Staff of Heller and Associates as part of a study of White House space in 1955 2/21/55 - 4/26/55 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - The Carter Reorganization Effort: A Review and Assessment by Ronald C Moe 9/16/80 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - National Journal 12/13/75 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Presidential Control of Senior Civil Service: Assessing the strategies of the Nixon Years, 1969 - 1976 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    by Richard L. Cole and David A. Caputo
  - News Articles [OMB] 10/27/73 - 8/24/74 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Nixon - OMB of Management (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Ford [reorganization of White House staff] 4/6/74 - 7/26/75 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Eisenhower as an Activist President: A Look at New Evidence Winter 1979 - 1980 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    by Fred I. Greenstein
  - Truman 3/1946 - 2/15/80 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Taxes, Deficits, and Inflation 12/1978 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    by David R. Cameron for Brookings Institute
  - Government and Medical Care (Box 24, Folder 1)
    Rosemary Stevens, no date, appears to be an address, last reference dated 1975
  - The Art and Craft of Policy Analysis 1979 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    by Aaron Wilavsky
  - Rational Fools: A Critique of the Behavioral Foundations of Economic Theory 1977 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    also included in the folder The expansion of the Public Economy: A Comparative Analysis by David R. Cameron, The American Political Science Review, Vol. 72; and "Qualifications and Entitlement Matrix: Germany and the US in the Present Era, 1979
  - Longitudinal Patterns of Policy Diffusion in Scandinavia, 1890-1965 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Inflation and Industrial Adjustment: The Politics of Supply 12/6/78 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    by John Zysman
  - The Brookings Institution Economic Studies Program, Taxation in the United Kingdom 5/1979 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    y Joseph A Pechman
  - 1972 - 1979 a report The German Marshall Fund of the United States Spring 1979 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    Also included is a research paper about the German health system, completed under The German Marshall Fund, regarding the health system, Chapter headings: The Nature, Sources and Limits of Physicians' Power; The Corporatist Context of Physician Politics; The Sources of Collective Power; The Nature and Sources of Discretionary Power; Limits on Collective Power - Countervailing Organizations; Limits on Collective Power - Reimbursement Methods; Limits on Discretionary Power - Economic Monitoring; Limits on Discretionary Power - The Board of Control Doctors; The Impact of Limits on Professional Power; Conclusion - Lessons for the United States
  - [The German Marshall Fund of the United States] Report on Current Activities 7/1979 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Trade Union Between Disruption and Stability 10/1979 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    by Colin Crouch
  - The Problem of Monopoly in Federal Health Policy 10/1979 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    by Debora A. Stone
  - Diagnosis and the Dole: The Function of Illness in American Distributive Politics Fall 1979 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - The Deserving Sick: Income-Maintenance Policy Towards the Ill and Disabled Winter 1978-1979 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Health Care Cost Containment in West Germany Summer 1979 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    by Deborah A. Stone
  - Physician as Gatekeeper: Illness Certification as a Rationing Device Spring 1979 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Backlash, Taxes and Welfare; Some Aggregate Tales, Told by Henrick Jess Madsen (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Public Reaction to the Growth of Taxation and Government Expenditure: A Preliminary Comparative Investigation 8/31/79 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    by Douglas A Hibbs, Jr. and Henrik Jess Madsen
  - LPP II 1958 - 2/1974 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Current Research in Social Security 1978 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - On the Development of Taxes in Western European Countries 7/22/77 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Trends and Problems in Post-War Public Expenditure development in Western Europe (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Political Development and the Growth of Social Insurance Programs in Scandinavia 1/17/78 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    by Stein Kuhnle
  - The Development of Unemployment Insurance in Western Europe (Box 25, Folder 5)
    Jens Alber
  - Education and Welfare State Entitlements in Europe and America 5/1978 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    Chapter 10 The Development of Welfare States in Europe and America, Semi-final Draft by Arnold J. Heidenheimer
  - The Growth of Social Insurance in Western Europe: Has Social Democracy Made a Difference? 8/12/79 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    by Jens Alber
  - Economic Inequality in the Advanced Capitalist Societies: A Comparative Analysis 1979 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    by David R. Cameron, Yale University
  - Comparative Politics and Public Policy 1980 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    by Barbara N. McLennan, published by Duxbury Press
  - Jones, Roger and [Sam Hughes] - Oral Interview Heclo/McGeary (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Oral History Interview with James H. Rowe, Jr by Jerry N. Hess 9/30/69 and 1/15/70 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    also included is an undated interview by Heclo
  - Transition '52 8/15/52 - 10/19/79 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Interview with John J. Corson (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Interview with James E. Webb 3/23/79 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Notes of Conversation with Mrs. Wayne (Grace) Coy 6/25/80 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Oral History (Box 26, Folder 5)
    Hand written notes
  - Administrative Diary of Donald C. Stone 1 of 2 4/25/39 - 9/7/39 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Administrative Diary of Donald C. Stone 2 of 2 11/4/39 - 4/7/40 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    Also included undated interview with Goodpastor Whitman, Saulnier, Gray, Staats, and Burns by HH
  - Memorandums [regarding management of the Executive Office of the President 3/6/40 - 7/28/80 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Staffing the Presidency by Bradley D. Nash 12/1952 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    a Planning Document published by The National Planning Association
  - Interview with Don Stone 9/3/79 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Information on the Means Furnished the President to Implement the Administrative Duties of His Office (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Memorandum on Organizing the Transition: A Tentative Checklist for the Weeks Between Election and Inaugural 9/15/60 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    by Richard E. Neustadt
  - an Historical Review of Plans for Presidential Staffing by Edward H. Hobbs 8/1956 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - The Bureau of the Budget: A View from the Inside by Percy Rappaport 3/1956 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - The Bureau of the Budget and Governmental Budgeting in Wartime 9/15/43 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    by Gustave A. Moe
  - The Transitional Presidency by Don K. Price (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Admin History [Applied Administrative Management American University] Spring 1948 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    also included is a transcription of a short exchange between Congressman Phillips and Lawton regarding the significant increase in Truman's office budget
  - Staff Meeting Division of Administrative Management 2/6/42 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Central Clearance [notes on discussion with Neustadt] 12/17/79 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - White House Regional Management Conference 10/26/61 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Donald C. Stone 6/13/45 - 4/2/80 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    administrative management activities of BOB, post-WW II federal government reorganization activities; US involvement in formulating UN Secretariat
  - IKE [sic] Correspondence about the re-write of a text book, "Comparative Public Policy" 4/6/79 - 11/7/79 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Draft Report on Executive Office 6/25/45 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Interview with Roy Ash 9/23/80 and 9/24/84 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Notes of conversation with Lee Auspitz 11/7/80 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Conversation with Arthur Minnich 7/31/80 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Interview with Charles S. Stauffacher 7/29/80 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Interview with Bradley Patterson 6/25/80 (Box 28, Folder 6)